Register of the Spanish subject collection, 1929-2009
Hoover Institution Archives
Spanish subject collection,
1929-2009
XX757
4 manuscript boxes, 1 oversize box, 5 videotape cassettes (2.2 linear feet)
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
Pamphlets, leaflets, bulletins, serial issues, election campaign literature, clippings, and video tapes, relating to various aspects of twentieth-century Spanish history and politics, and especially to the Spanish Civil War and pro-Republican Spanish refugees in France.
Administrative Information
Access
Collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Materials were acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Scope and Content of Collection
Pamphlets, leaflets, bulletins, serial issues, election campaign literature, clippings, and video tapes, relating to various aspects of twentieth-century Spanish history and politics, and especially to the Spanish Civil War and pro-Republican Spanish refugees in France.
Indexing Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the library's online public access catalog.
Refugees.; Spaniards--France.; Elections--Spain.; Spain--History--20th century.; Spain--History--Civil War, 1936-1939.; Spain--Politics and government--20th century.; Video tapes
Collection Contents
- SUBJECT FILE, 1929-1993 (Box 1-2)
  Newspaper issues, pamphlets, propaganda placards, memorabilia, and clippings, relating to the Spanish Civil War, Spanish emigres in France, Catalonia, and other aspects of Spanish history. Mainly in Spanish
- OVERSIZE FILE, 1990-1993 (Box 3)
  Printed matter issued by various political parties.
- AUDIO-VISUAL FILE, 1983 (Cassette cabinet)
  Four video cassettes relating to Spanish history.
Container List
SEE CARD CATALOG FOR INCREMENTS THAT MAY HAVE BEEN RECEIVED AFTER DEC. 1994
- SUBJECT FILE, 1929-1993
  - General
    - General. Miscellaneous printed matter (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Basque region. Miscellaneous printed matter, 1992-1993 (Folder 2)
    - Catalonia. Printed material, election flyers, stickers and flyers of the Socialist Party of Catalonia, and proceedings of its 4th Congress, ca. 1931-1987 (Folder 3-6)
  - History
    - Civil War, 1936-1939
      - General. Press releases, flyers, leaflets, postcards, speeches, poster catalog, and printed copy of a work by Joan Miro, 1937-1992 (Folder 7-8)
      - Same as above (Box 2, Folder 1-4)
      - Spaniards in France. Miscellaneous printed matter issued by pro-Republican Spanish refugees in France, 1943-1946 (Folder 5)
      - Whelan, Paul. Short letter with biographical listing entitled "Soviet Airmen in the Spanish Civil War, 1936-1939," 1991-1992 (Folder 6)
  - Political parties
    - Bloque Obrero y Campesino. Election flyers, 1936? (Folder 7)
    - Communism. Issue of Bandera Roja, publication of the Communist Organization of Spain, and a printed copy of El Socialist Workers Party y La Guerra Imperialista, by the Grupo Espaqol en Mixico de la IV Internacional, 1945-1974 (Folder 8)
    - Partido Socialista Obrero Espanol. Brochures, leaflets, relating to the June 1986 general elections, as well as a 4-year activities report. In Spanish (Folder 9-10)
- OVERSIZE FILE, 1990-1993
  - Printed matter issued by various political parties (Box 3)
- AUDIO-VISUAL FILE, 1983. Video cassettes
  - 1 untitled (Tape-cabinet Tape cabinet)
  - 2 cassettes produced by Granada Video, entitled "The Spanish Civil War," 1983
  - 1 cassette entitled, "Rescatadas del Olvido. Mujeres Bajo el Franquismo", Universidad de Castilla-La Mancha
- Incremental Materials (Box 4-5)
  This addition to the collection has not yet been described. Please let the Hoover Institution Archives know if you would like to see this material described. Contact us at hooverarchivesinfo@stanford.edu